Mary Metlay Kaufman Papers, 1917-1994
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES VII. SPEECHES
  - Vietnam War
    - "A Call to Moratorium: the War, the Draft, the Ghetto," Rutgers U., 1968 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - "The Consequences of an Illegal War: The Spock-Coffin Indictments," Columbia Law School: notes and flier, circa 1968 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - "Solidarity on Indochina": draft, undated (Box 76, Folder 17)
- SERIES VIII. RESEARCH AND SUBJECT FILES
  - American Civil Liberties Union (includes Abraham Isserman), 1977 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Anti-communism
    - General, 1955-77 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Anti-communist cases, 1949-53 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - F.B.I. files bill ("Jenks law"), 1957 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Richard Harris, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - McCarran Act, 1965 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Paul Robeson, undated (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - The Rosenbergs, Morton Sobell, and Angela Davis (re: book and documentary): reviews, correspondence, drafts, clippings, and printed material, 1955-74, undated (Box 77, Folder 8-9)
    - Smith Act: typescript, 1953 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified notes and drafts, undated (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Biko, Stephen, 1977 (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Blacks and the peace movement (includes commentary on National Lawyers' Guild by Fania Davis), 1982-83, undated (Box 77, Folder 13-14)
  - Book lists, 1972-74, undated (Box 77, Folder 15)
  - Central and South America (Box 77, Folder 16)
  - Civil disobedience (includes paper by Michael Kaufman), circa 1966-68, undated (Box 78, Folder 1-3)
  - Cold War, 1970-94 (Box 78, Folder 4-5)
  - Angela Davis, 1971, undated (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Germany
    - General, 1966-67, 1990, undated (Box 78, Folder 7-8)
    - German legal system (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - German unification (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - U.S. Committee for Friendship with the German Democratic Republic, 1985- (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - International law (Box 78)
    [SEE Nuremberg and international law]
  - Iran-Contra, 1985-87, undated (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Korea, 1976-84 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Labor, undated (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous: printed materials, clippings, and notes, 1968-95, undated (Box 79, Folder 1-3)
  - Nuclear disarmament
    - General: articles, printed materials, and newspaper clippings, 1978-94, undated (Box 79, Folder 4-5)
    - Big Mountain Support Group, Berkeley, CA, undated (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Carter's foreign policy and nuclear weapons (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Greenham Women against cruise missiles v. Ronald Reagan, 1984 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - International law and nuclear weapons (includes Richard Falk, Lee Meyrowitz, and Jack Sanderson), 1958-84, undated (Box 80, Folder 1-23)
    - International Physicians for the Prevention of Nuclear War, 1985 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Neutron bomb, circa 1962-81 (Box 81, Folder 2-8)
      [SEE ALSO SERIES V. ORGANIZATIONS AND CONFERENCES - Lawyers' Emergency Committee on the Illegality of Nuclear Weapons]
    - Nevada - International Scientific Symposium on a Nuclear Test Ban, 1986-88, undated (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Non-legal articles on nuclear weapons (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Nuclear freeze debate, 1982 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Nuclear test ban treaty, circa 1987-88 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Reagan's foreign policy, 1981, undated (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Rocky Flats, Denver, CO (Gordon Albi), undated (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - SALT II, 1981 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Scientists' appeal for abolition of nuclear war, 1955 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Soviet Union and nuclear weapons, 1978-81 (Box 82, Folder 7-10)
    - Star Wars (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Claire Sherman Thomas, 1983, undated (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - E.P. Thompson, 1981 (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Trident (includes Robert Aldridge, Shelley Douglass and James Douglass, Ground Zero and Pacific Life Community), 1975-83 (Box 82, Folder 14-20)
    - Upper Heyford Ploughshares (England), 1990 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified notes and drafts on disarmament, undated (Box 83, Folder 2-3)
  - Nuclear power, circa 1978-79 (Box 83, Folder 4-8)
  - Nuremberg and Nazis
    - I.G. Farben and Karl von Krauch (includes Aaron Tilton, Gina Kalla and Brian Conlan), 1948, 1987 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Nazis: general, 1950-78, undated (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Nazis: R-S, 1950-78, undated (Box 84, Folder 1-2)
    - Nuremberg principles and international law
      [SEE ALSO Vietnam and Nuclear disarmament]
      - General: printed materials, articles, and notes, undated (Box 84, Folder 3-4)
      - "The Promise of Nuremberg..." (material for article), 1981, undated (Box 84, Folder 5)
      - Nuremberg and Iran-Contra, circa 1987 (Box 84, Folder 6)
      - Theories of international law and Self-determination, undated (Box 84, Folder 7)
      - "War crimes," undated (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Nuremberg Tribunal
      - Harvard Law Review: articles, 1947-56, undated (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - National Lawyers' Guild article, undated (Box 85, Folder 2)
      - 20th anniversary of Tribunal (includes American Friends' Service Committee), circa 1966 (Box 85, Folder 3)
        [SEE ALSO SERIES V. ORGANIZATIONS AND CONFERENCES - National Lawyers' Guild - Conferences, 1966]
    - Unidentified drafts and notes (Box 85, Folder 4-7)
  - Racism: clippings and printed materials (Box 85, Folder 8-9)
  - Vietnam War
    - General, 1965-67 (Box 86, Folder 1-5)
    - American Friends' Service Committee, 1973 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - China and Vietnam, circa 1978-79 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Honeywell Project (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Kissinger, Shawcross, and Cambodia, circa 1979 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - White House National Security Wiretaps (Nixon and Haig), undated (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Vietnam and Nuremberg
      - General, 1966-75, undated (Box 87, Folder 6-8)
      - Benjamin Spock and draft resistance (includes letter from Michael Kaufman), circa 1966-68 (Box 87, Folder 9)
      - Telford Taylor: transcript of television interview, 1971 (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - War Powers Act, 1980 (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - Weinstock, Louis, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 12)
- OVERSIZED MATERIAL
  - SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL
    - Articles: original (photocopy in box 1) (Map-case Flat file)
    - Memorabilia: Nathan Metlay's certificate of naturalization, 1924 (Map-case Flat file)
  - SERIES III. LEGAL PRACTICE
    - Smith Act
      - Publicity: Clippings (originals of photocopies in box 4,8) (Map-case Flat file)
      - Smith Act Victims Self Defense Committee: poster, "We Appeal to you for a Fair Trial" (includes color copy), n.d. (Map-case Flat file)
    - Willie McGee v. [State of Mississippi]: Civil Rights Congress flier, 1950 (Map-case Flat file)
    - Dialogue Publications: Articles of Incorporation, 1964 (Map-case Flat file)
  - SERIES V. ORGANIZATIONS
    - Lawyer's Committee on American Policy: statements, undated (Map-case Flat file)
    - National Lawyers' Guild - New York City Chapter: newspapers (Map-case Flat file)
  - SERIES VII. SPEECHES
    - Posters (3), undated (Map-case Flat file)
  - SERIES VIII. RESEARCH AND SUBJECT FILES
    - Vietnam war: flyer, "Extra Blatt," 1971 (Map-case Flat file)